# **NGUYEN HOANG VIET**

Mobile Software Engineer (Junior)

# 1999

0398 560 520







#### **ABOUT MYSELF**

I am working as a Mobile Developer (React Native) with more than 1 year of experience. Recently, I've been doing more research on Flutter and have worked on several projects that use the Bloc pattern.

I am so welcome and happy to learn, to share and to talk about IT knowledge.

I have positive attitude and can execute on difficult tasks. I am always energetic and eager to learn new skills. Ability to work independently as well as in a team with high responsibility.



### **WORK EXPERIENCES**

### Mobile developer

ITBee-Solutions | 11/2020 - Present

Working as mobile developer.

- The main person initiate the project, base config (Redux, Restful Api, Base Components...), build the source's structure, merge code, resolve the React-native's problem with team's members...
- · Training for new interns
- · Join and learn Swift to maintain iOS project with mobile project manager.

#### Internship / Fresher Mobile developer

Ant-Tech | 05/2020 - 10/2020

Internship process as mobile dev position.

- Using React-native with Hook, Redux Saga, folder constructed according to Ignite boilerplate. How to upgrade new React-native's version, upgrade new library's version.
- Using TypeScript / ES6 syntax, refactor code to look cleaner
- · More Git skills: Stash, revert, merge, config handle
- Build new Android and iOS (Xcode) version, build and test Android bundle with bundle tool
- Daily report, meeting skill, write report document, resolve the problem...

### Student / Working with my teacher

09/2019 - 05/2020

The first time to join and work with real project. Understanding the process of product (from initiation to release) working with BA, dev, tester, designer.

- My first meet with React Native, Redux / Redux observable, Components, Props / States, React Native's lifecycle
- · JavaScript syntax, how to working (run, debug...) with React Native
- · Apply Git's skills to manager real project's source code

### TYPICAL PROJECTS

DAYGO 08/2021 - present

Project Description: DayGo delivery app is a connection platform between businesses and drivers, an application for shippers, helping shippers to manage and track their work as well as help administrators track delivery activities more easily right away. on the phone

Mobile team size: 2 (App reference: iOS, Android )

07/2021 - 09/2021

Project Description: BEE AFFILIATE SYSTEM Comprehensive argument transfer solution to help businesses manage and expand distribution channels, agents, collaborators, memberships and affiliates effectively

Mobile team size: 2 (App reference: iOS, Android)

### BeeBeauty

02/2021 - 08/2021

Project Description: BeeBeauty is an application with main features are Spa schedule booking, sell products, remember customer's information for Spa chain system.

Mobile team size: 3 (App reference: iOS, Android)

### Responsibilities:

- Mobile project's leader (Assign tasks, solve problems and guide for team's members. Error handler in development process...)
- Initiate project, config base, core (Redux, Redux-Saga, Service, build folder structure following Ignite pattern, create common base components...)
- Fix bug, refactor code, research to optimization structures, performance and manage source code with Git (Merge code, conflict handle, basic review...)
- Build iOS version to TestFlight and Android (apk, aab)
- Deploy applications to App Store and Google Play Store.

### SKILLS

#### **Technical**

Mobile Applications

React native / Flutter

Redux / Bloc

JavaScript / TypeScript / Dart

Worked with iOS / Swift

#### Self Skills

Communicate effectively

Team player

Problem solving

#### Knowledge

Understanding about the Product Management Process

Understanding about software design, some design patterns, RestfulAPI

Have experience working with Firebase, Notification, Socket.io, Deploy app..

## EDUCATION

### Software Engineer

Ho Chi Minh City Vocational Training College 2017 - 2020

### LANGUAGES

Vietnamese (Native)

English (Reading, Basic Speaking, Writing)

### INTERESTS

Reading, Watching, Listening

Play sports (Badminton, Gym...)

Photography

### **ACTIVITIES**

### 15km Finisher

LAAN Ultra trial 2019 (2019)

Inside the projects: Ignite pattern structure, Redux-Saga, TypeScript, Hook, react-native-config, one-signal, firebase, otp, notification, google map..

#### AnyBackup

01/2021 - 02/2021

Project Description: AnyBackup is an iOS IOT application using with auto-backup device (can connect with  ${\sf USB}\ or\ {\sf SD}\ card)\ to\ backup\ or\ restores\ data\ (photos, music\ldots)\ from\ iPhone\ to\ auto-backup\ devices\ and\ vice$ 

Mobile team size: 2

#### Responsibilities:

- Research, Build UI and features following customer's requirements
- Fix bugs, refactor code, build new version...

Inside the project: Swift 5, SnapKit, MVC design pattern

### Polymate

05/2020 - 10/2020

Project Description: Polymate is a social network which has the particularity of relying on a news feed developed by its own users, which changes in real time taking into account the geolocated position of the

Mobile team size: 4 (in Viet Nam, reference: polymate.fr/nous)

### Responsibilities:

- Support and recommend the way to resolve the problems, new feature ideas directly with client.
- · Build new screen, working with Restful API.
- $\bullet~$  Fix bug, refactor code and manager source code with Git.
- Build iOS version to TestFlight and Android (apk, aab).
- Write documentation for future maintainers.

 $\textbf{Inside the project:} \ \textbf{Ignite pattern structure, Redux-Saga, TypeScript, Hook, react-native-config, one-signal...}$ 



### PERSONAL PROJECTS

#### **EnglishVocab**

Project description: I have developed this application for play mini game to learn english. This application can login with Google account, message together and available on Google Play now (in the process to develope new version with Flutter).

Project's target: Working with SQLite to save and query data, crawl data with Jsoup, Google Services to develope message, notification feature...

Improve logic handle skill and mindset to resolve the problems.

Deploy app to Google Play and more...

Reference: Available on Play Store



You can find more my personal projects was public on My Github (+50 repositories) . All of them are developed when I have free time or after my work hours on the purpose of practicing skills or learning something new.